PHILIP BROWNE

 • Washington DC/Baltimore | ☐ (443) 459-7382 | ☑ pbrowne@gmail.com | ♠ PhilipBrowne | Im PhilipBrowneTech | ∰ www.philiprowne.com

Full Stack Software Engineer with a passion for helping people through technology and finding ways to efficiently and collaboratively solve problems. Dedicated and detail-oriented professional with a background of more than a decade as an orchestral musician and a proven record of success in multiple industries.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front End: JavaScript, React.js, AJAX, HTML5, CSS, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, jQuery, Phaser.js, WordPress

Back End: Node.js, Express.js, Python, Flask, Apache, RESTful API Development

Database: SQL, PostgreSQL, SQLite, MySQL, MongoDB, ElasticSearch

Testing: Jasmine, Jest, Mocha, React Testing Library, PyUnit **DevOps/Deployment:** Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, Heroku, Netlify **Miscellaneous:** Git, GitHub, GitLab, Jira, Linux Terminal, Selenium

PROJECTS

Voter Info / Repository Link

2021

- Full-Stack Voter Information Application using Google Civic Information, EasyPost, and MapQuest APIs
- Technologies Used: JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, AJAX, Axios, Python, Flask, Bcrypt, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL

Space Force / Repository Link

2021

- Full-Stack Project for Mintbean.io Hiring Hackathon. Mintbean Star Award Winner for "exemplary achievement in the field of web development"
- Technologies Used: JavaScript, PhaserJS, JavaScript State Machine, Bootstrap, Python, Flask, Bcrypt, SQLAlchemy PostgreSQL

WORK EXPERIENCE

Junior Full Stack Developer

2021 - Present

Relavistic

- Developing and maintaining both independent and collaborative projects for small startup specializing in new concepts in data analytics, artificial intelligence, and machine learning to enable automatic end-to-end data collection, processing, and analysis.
- Building scalable highly reliable products and maintaining uptime of existing applications.

Communications Administrator / Technical Support

2021

Unitarian Universalist Church of Silver Spring

- Serving as Office Administrator for 200+ member congregation as the central point of contact and technical support.
- Managing membership database and finding ways to effectively promote congregation, while also managing UUCSS
 Website via WordPress platform.

Freelance Musician 2009 – Present

Professional Orchestral French Horn player with experience working with groups such as the Baltimore Symphony, Virginia Symphony, Richmond Symphony, Pittsburgh Opera, and National Philharmonic, among others.

EDUCATION

Johns Hopkins University, Baltimore, Maryland

Graduated with BM in 2009, GPD in 2012

Bachelor of Music, French Horn Performance; Graduate Performance Diploma (GPD), French Horn Performance

Yale University Graduate School of Music

2012-2014

Springboard Software Engineering Career Track Fellowship

2021

An 800-hour fellowship that covers key aspects of front-end web development, back-end web development, databases, and data structures and algorithms. Modules include learning resources, practice exercises, projects, and career-related coursework.